okay what are the dynamics a biblical
好吧，圣经的动力是什么
change and in that situation what we
改变，在那种情况下，我们
have to do is ask the question you know
要做的就是问你知道的问题
what is the problem and then when we do
问题是什么，然后我们什么时候做
that and we ask what is the problem we
那我们问我们有什么问题
need to be specific in that situation
需要在那种情况下具体
and we need to think biblically so in
我们需要圣经这样认为的
Ephesians chapter 5 and that's really
以弗所书第5章，那是真的
what you should have open before you
你应该在你面前打开什么
this morning as we look through this
今天早上我们看一下这个
passage in particular Paul gives
保罗给出了特别的段落
specific example he says that the person
具体的例子他说那个人
needs to speak the truth in verse 15 he
需要在第15节说出真理
has to speak the truth in love and then
必须用爱说出真相
as the text of goes down he says
他说 ，随着文本的下降
therefore laying aside falsehood speak
因此放下谎言说话
the truth each one of you with his
你们每个人都带着他的真相
neighbor he says be angry so you can be
邻居他说生气所以你可以
righteously angry but do not sin and
公然生气， 但不要犯罪
don't let the sin the Sun go down on
不要让太阳落山的罪恶
your anger and then he tells you in
你的愤怒，然后他告诉你
verse 20 and 28 let him who stoled still
第20节和第28节让他静止不动
no longer but rather he must labor
不再是他必须劳动
performing with his own hands what is
用自己的双手表演是什么
good so that he will have something to
好，这样他就会有所收获
share with the one who is in need when
与有需要的人分享
is a thief not a thief when he quits
当他退出时，小偷不是小偷
stealing no when he quits stealing and
当他退出偷窃时偷窃没有
he gets a job and he gets a job and he
他得到一份工作，他找到了工作，他
earns enough not only to supply his own
赚取足够的钱不仅供给自己
family but he's giving to others when
家人，但他什么时候给别人
the thief who is greedy and steals
那个贪婪和偷窃的小偷
becomes the giver who shares what he has
成为分享他所拥有的东西的送礼者
with others who in there I need that's
与其他人在那里我需要那个
the difference now look at the next
差异现在看下一个
verse let unknown wholesome words just
诗歌只是让未知的健康话语
stop saying unwholesome words just stop
别说停止说不善言辞了
it if you've if you've heard that little
如果你听到那么一点，那就好吧
clip and huh just stop it yeah I I don't
剪辑和呵呵只是停止它是啊我没有
know if Newhart got that from the
知道Newhart是否从中得到了
Apostle Paul but Paul says you know let
使徒保罗但保罗说你知道让
no unwholesome words proceed from your
没有不善言辞的话从你的
mouth that's northern - but he's saying
那个北方的嘴- 但他在说
you just stop saying unwholesome words
你只是停止说不健康的话
stop it
停下来
then what but put on rather he must then
然后穿上而不是他必须
what put on good words only such a word
什么只能说出这么好的话
as is good for edification according to
为造就好根据
the need of the moment that it might
它可能需要的那一刻
minister grace to those who hear not a
部长恩惠给那些听不到的人
matter of just stop saying bad words
只是停止说坏话的问题
okay so you just keep your mouth shut
好吧，你只是闭上你的 嘴
no you find out a good word a good word
不， 你找到一个好词，一个好词
that will build people up at the right
将 在合适的 人建立起来
moment that will minister grace oh
那将会赐予恩典的时刻哦
that's a mouthful and oh that's hard to
这是一个拗口哦这是很难
do yeah that's why you need to pray and
是的，这就是你需要祈祷的原因
ask the Holy Spirit to give you the will
请求圣灵赐给你意志
and the power to do it to change your
和动力去做更改
thinking and stop you from coming up
从 上来想阻止你
with those instant comebacks that are so
那些即时复出就是如此
nasty when somebody says something nasty
当有人说出令人讨厌的东西时会很讨厌
to you if you're like me I've got a
如果你像我一样，我有一个
zinger that I mean this automatically
zinger ，我的意思是自动
comes to my mind my brain may be going
在我看来，我的大脑可能正在发展
an old age but I can still excuse me I
年老但我仍然可以原谅我
can still think of something nasty to
仍然可以想到一些令人讨厌的东西
say immediately when somebody says
当有人说时，立刻说
something nasty to me but what you're
对我来说很 讨厌，但你是什么
supposed to say is something that
应该说的是那样的
ministers grace what is Grace unmerited
部长们恩惠恩典是不合适的
favor they say a zinger they deserve a
他们赞成他们应该得到一个zinger
zinger but they say a zinger to you
zinger 但是他们对你说了一个zinger
you're a Christian and you say a
你是一个基督徒，你说一个
blessing back to them well that's
祝福他们好了
different and then it says in verse 31
不同，然后它在第31节说
let all bitterness and wrath and anger
让所有的苦涩，愤怒和愤怒
and clamor and slander be put away from
并且要求喧嚣和诽谤
you along with all malice and then be
你和所有的恶意，然后是
kind to one another tender-hearted
善待彼此
forgiving each other just as God in
像上帝一样原谅对方
Christ has forgiven you so we put away
基督原谅了你，所以我们就放弃了
anger and wrath malice and slander and
愤怒和愤怒恶意和诽谤和
clamor and we put on a tender-hearted
吵闹，我们心地投入了热情
forgiving spirit because we've been
宽容的精神， 因为我们一直都是
forgiven in Christ and so that this
在基督里原谅了这一点
change process is described and it paul
改变过程被描述并且它保罗
deals with it specifically is it
特别是处理它
specific stop stealing get a job earn
具体停止偷取工作赚取
enough for yourself and start giving to
足够自己开始给予
others it's pretty specific it's pretty
其他它非常具体，非常漂亮
concrete because people change
具体是因为人们改变了
in the concrete they don't change in the
在具体中他们没有改变
abstract so if you say to somebody well
抽象所以，如果你对某人说得好
you need to learn to be careful as a
你需要学会小心为
driver you know you say I'm sinning
司机， 你知道你说我在犯罪
because I'm not a careful driver and
因为我不是一个谨慎的司机和
careless drivers cause accidents well
粗心的司机导致事故发生
how do you become a careful driver well
你如何成为一个谨慎的驾驶以及
you did how are you uncared well well I
你做了什么，你怎么也不好我
roll through stop signs
翻滚停车标志
okay that's specific and I rush up on
好吧，那是具体的，我匆匆上去
stop signs and stoplights frightening my
停止标志和红绿灯吓坏我的
passengers that's specific okay and is
乘客这是具体的很好，而且是
that sin well think about it is it rude
罪恶好好想想它是不礼貌的
is it unkind is rudeness a sin his lack
不仁慈是粗鲁是他缺乏的罪
of kindness is sin yes if the people are
仁慈是罪，如果人民是
wondering is he ever going to stop and
不知道是他曾经再停下来
they're pumping on the brake on their
他们在他们身上踩刹车
side of the car there isn't one there
车的一侧没有一个
then it's time for you to learn you know
那时你是时候学习你了解的
you need to slow up and let them know
你需要放慢速度并让他们知道
you do see the light and you are going
你确实看到了光， 你要去
to stop so we're applying it
停止所以我们正在应用它
specifically in every area and now in
特别是在每个领域，现在在
this context as well think biblically is
这个背景以及圣经的思考是
he codependent or a man pleaser you know
他相互依赖或者你知道一个人欢心
why he grew up in a home with a drunken
为什么他在醉酒的家里长大
father and he never knew whether the
父亲和他从不知道是否
father was gonna be happy drunk glad
父亲快乐醉得高兴
drunk sad drunk mad drunk you know and
喝醉了，喝醉了， 喝醉了，你知道
so whatever he did depending on what
所以无论他根本取决于什么
kind of drunk he was in he didn't know
有点醉，他在他不知道
what would please him and so he's
什么会让他高兴，所以他是
codependent for his happiness on that
依赖于他的快乐
person no he's trying to be a man
人不，他想成为一个男人
pleaser what you need to do is please
拜托你需要做的就是请
God what does God wants you to honor
上帝要求你尊重上帝
your father and your mother even if your
即使你的父亲和你的母亲也是如此
father or your mother is a drunkard how
父亲或你的母亲是醉汉怎么样
do you honor them how do you show
你是否尊重他们你是如何表现出来的？
respect for them but how do you then do
尊重他们，但你怎么做
what would please God what would honor
什么会取悦上帝什么会荣誉
God in this response and it doesn't
上帝在这种反应中并没有
matter whether he's mad drunk a patron
不管他是不是疯了醉了一个赞助人
sad drunk I'm gonna do what pleases God
伤心的喝醉了， 我会做上帝喜欢的事
and whatever reaction he has is his
无论他有什么反应都是他的
reaction I'm not dependent upon his
反应我不依赖他
reaction give it biblical terminology is
反应给它圣经术语是
it an affair that sounds fun but if it's
这听起来很有趣，但如果是的话
adultery
通奸
is it a gay alternative lifestyle that
它是一个同性恋的素食生活方式
sounds fun or is it a perversion and sin
听起来很有趣，还是一种变态和罪恶
we must determine what we're gonna call
我们必须确定我们要称之为什么
it is it alcoholism or is it drunkenness
是酒精中毒还是酗酒
and remember when you call it what it is
并记得当你称之为它是什么
you actually then will give people hope
你实际上会给人们希望
because God died for sinners and he died
因为上帝为罪人而死，他就死了
for sin and therefore there is
为罪，因此有
redemption from sin so next question is
从罪中赎回所以下一个问题是
what have you done about the problem and
你有什么话对问题进行，
the reason there you want to ask that
你想要问的原因
because you want to know actually what
因为你想知道究竟是什么
they did do because what they did do may
他们这样做是因为他们所做的可能
have complicated the problem Cain what
复杂的问题该隐是什么
you do about the problem you you weren't
你解决的问题是你不是
feeling good about your brother's
对你哥哥的感觉很好
offering being accepted and yours not
提供被接受而你的被接受
being accepted what do you do about it I
被接受你对此做了什么我
killed my brother
杀了我哥哥
okay we got a complication David what
好吧，我们得到一个复杂的大卫什么
did you do about it
你做了什么
I you got caught in adultery and she's
我，你被通奸，她是
gonna have a baby well I I lied about it
要生个孩子，我会撒谎
did that help no not really the guy
这对那个家伙有帮助吗
didn't buy the lie and well then what
没有买谎，那么什么
did you do about it well I killed a guy
你做得好吗我杀了一个人
that didn't help either see what have
这并没有帮助看看有
they done about it you know that may
他们做到了，你知道可能
complicate the problem and so you need
使问题复杂化，所以你需要
to know what they've done about it you
要知道，他们已经对此做了什么你
need to ask questions that will give you
需要提出能给你的问题
an understanding in that area what's
在那个领域的理解是什么
everybody done about it
大家都是这样做的
come on Saturday morning I know but
星期六早上来，我知道但是
you're awake I can tell most of you
你很清醒， 我可以告诉大多数人
anyways all right what have they done
反正没事做了什么
about it everybody's done it prayed
关于它，每个人都做了它祈祷
about it what did you do but I prayed
关于它你做了什么，但我祈祷
about it well what did you pray how
关于它，你是怎么祈祷的
often did you pray what did you expect
经常你祈祷你期待什么
that God would do in relationship to
上帝会与之相关
that prayer did you expect God to answer
你希望上帝回答这个祷告
what is your understanding of God and
你对上帝的理解是什么？
you're going to learn from that you're
你会从你 学习
gonna ask more questions you've got to
要问你有 更多问题
gather really good data so we've talked
收集非常好的数据，所以我们已经谈过了
about this what has been done or what is
关于这已经做了什么或是什么
being done may I have a overshadow or
做完可能我有阴影或
conceal the actual heart issue
隐瞒实际的心脏问题
that needs to be addressed so the man
那个 男人 需要解决这个问题
comes in the man's depressed and you say
你说 ，这个男人很沮丧
when did the depression start and he
抑郁症何时开始，他
says Oh two weeks ago and what happened
两个星期前 哦，发生了什么事
then anything happened at that time well
然后任何在那个时候发生的很好
I lost my job well that's depressing
我失去了工作，令人沮丧
right so you could just move on from
对，所以你可以继续前进
there no well what happened what was the
那里发生了什么事情
reason you lost your job well I got
你得失你工作的原因
angry at the boss well what happened
老板很生气，发生了什么事
when that scene what would I have seen
当那个场景我会看到什么
if I had been a bug on the wall when you
如果我是你的墙上的虫子
got angry with your boss well you would
你会对老板生气
have seen me tell him off and tell him
看到我告诉他并告诉他
that his opinion wasn't worth anything
他的意见是不值得的事情
and that he didn't really understand
他并不是真的明白
what was happening on the floor where I
在我所在的地板上发生了什么
worked and then you would have seen me
工作，然后你会看到我
shove him against the wall okay
把他推到墙上好吧
has that ever happened before well yes
曾经有过这样的事情
how many times have you ever lost a job
你有多少次失去工作
because of your anger in the past yes I
因为你过去的愤怒是我
have and several times and so now you're
有几次，所以现在你
getting a pattern and depression which
得到一个模式和抑郁症
is the presenting problem
是提出的问题
maybe concealing a real heart issue of
也许隐瞒真正的心脏问题
anger and pride that needs to be dealt
需要处理的愤怒和骄傲
with before you're going to get to the
在你要去之前
issues that really need to be dealt with
真正需要要处理的问题
so the next thing now is interpretation
所以接下来的事情就是解释
in the sense of what does the scripture
从经文的意义上说
say about the problem you need to
说出你需要的问题
understand the problem what does the
了解问题是什么
Bible say about depression melancholy
圣经说关于忧郁的忧郁
what does the Bible say about anger what
圣经对愤怒的说法是什么
does the Bible say about thinking that
圣经是否会这么想
your boss is just plain dumb and doesn't
你的老板只是愚蠢而不是
really understand is that pride
真正明白的是那种自豪感
partially well you've got to understand
部分你已经明白了
that so let's look now at Ephesians and
那么现在让我们看看以弗所书和
chapter 4 and let's start with verse 17
第四章，让我们从第17节开始
but if you went back to verse 1 you'd
但如果你回到第1节，你就会
see that this chapter starts remember
看到本章开始记得
chapters 1 chapter 2 chapter 3 don't
第1章第2章第3章没有
disassociate that from what we're doing
将这与我们正在做的事情分开
here in fact if you're gonna start with
事实上， 如果你要开始
a person and you're going to give them
一个人，你会给他们
homework
家庭作业
and you're going to assign to them
而且你要分配给他们
Ephesians 4:29 if you look in your notes
以弗所书4:29如果你看着你的笔记
over to about the fifth page in this
大约在这第五页
you'll see a discovering wonderful
你会看到一个奇妙的发现
things she should look like this the
她应该看起来像这样的东西
discovering wonderful things she it has
发现她拥有的美好事物
observation interpretation application
观察解释应用
and the example is let no unwholesome
而且这个例子不让人不健康
word proceed from your mouth you're
从你口中说出你的话
gonna have them memorize and meditate
要让他们记住和冥想
think on Ephesians 4:29 for the week and
本周和以弗所书4:29一起思考
you're gonna have them pray that back to
你会让他们祈祷回来
God we'll talk about why you want them
上帝， 我们会谈谈你为什么要他们
to do that in a few minutes but you're
在几分钟内做到这一点， 但你是
gonna have them pray that back to God
要让他们祈祷回到上帝面前
now in chapter 4 verse 1 it says
现在在第4章第1节中说
therefore I the prisoner of the Lord
因此，我是主的囚犯
therefore based on what chapters 1
因此根据第1章的内容
chapter 2 chapter 3 what's that all
第2章第3章是什么
about well it's about being redeemed
关于好这是关于被赎回
it's about being born again by faith by
它是关于通过信仰重生的
grace through faith it's all about the
通过信仰的恩典， 这完全是关于
fact in Chapter that God can do anything
在章节中，上帝可以做任何事情
in fact if you just back up to chapter 3
其实如果你只是备份到第3章
and you look at right at the end of
你看到了最后的结果
chapter 3 and look at what it says that
第3章，看看 它说，
you know in verse 19 the love of Christ
你在第19节中知道基督的爱
that surpasses knowledge and be filled
超越知识并被填补
up with the fullness of God and now to
与上帝的丰满和现在
him who is able to do far more
能够做得更多的人
abundantly beyond all we ask or think
我们所要求或思考的远远不止
according to the power that works within
根据内在的力量
us to him be the glory in the church in
我们对他来说是教会里的荣耀
Christ Jesus to all generations forever
基督耶稣永远为世世代代
and ever amen so it's what is the
从来没有阿门所以它就是这样的
context here because of the gospel
这里的背景是因为福音
because of God's grace because of his
因为上帝的恩典，因为他的
power you're gonna grow up and know the
权力，你会长大，知道
love of Christ and and you are going to
爱基督，你会去
be then able to pray and see God do
然后能够祈祷，看到上帝做
things in you that that go beyond your
在你身上超越你的东西
ability to understand and thing and then
理解和事物的能力然后
in chapter 4 therefore I the prisoner of
因此，在第4章中我是囚犯
the Lord in plural to walk in a manner
主以复数行事
worthy gonna be talking about our walk
值得谈谈我们的行走
in the Lord he's going to talk about
在主他会谈论
that again in chapter 5 and in chapter 5
再次是在第5章第5章
he's gonna tell us in verse one we're to
他会在第一节告诉我们
be imitators and we are to walk in love
是模仿者，我们要走进爱河
and down in verse 8 of chapter 5 he's
在第5章的第8节中，他是
gonna say you were formerly of darkness
会说你以前是黑暗的
now you're in the light and you are to
现在你处在光明之中，你就是这样
walk as children of the light so this
走路作为光明的孩子所以这个
theme of walking and the idea is your
走路的主题和想法是你的
walk characterizes you if I knew you
如果我认识你，你会走路
well enough I could watch you walk down
好吧， 我可以看着你走下去
the street and and recognise you by your
街道，并通过你的认可你
walk sitting in a hospital room one day
有一天走在医院的病房里
and visiting with the man and he said
和那个男人一起拜访他说
here comes my wife and you know I looked
我妻子来了，你知道我看了
at the door and all you can see from the
在门口， 你可以从中看到
door is the other side of the hall but
门是大厅的另一边但是
then I listened I could hear someone
然后我听了我能听见某人
steps coming down the hall and his wife
走下大厅和他的妻子的步骤
came around the corner about that how'd
谈到了怎么样
you know that was your wife I recognized
你知道那是我认可的你的妻子
her walk coming down the hall he
她步行走进大厅
recognized her walk coming down the hall
认出她走下大厅
and so your walk characterizes you but
所以你的步行就是你的特色
now go back to chapter 4 and look at
现在回到第4章看看
verse 17 and what it says there is so
第17节和它所说的有什么
this I said now remember the Greek
我说现在记得希腊人
language pile the words up together so
语言堆积在一起所以
this I say and affirm together with the
这个我说和肯定一起
Lord what's Paul doing he's trying to
主什么是保罗做他试图
get your attention
引起你的注意
he can't highlight it he can't put it
他无法强调它不能说出来
all in capitals he can't make it in bold
所有在首都他都不能用粗体
on his computer he doesn't have one and
在他的电脑上，他没有一个和
so what he does do is he piles up words
所以他所做的就是堆积语言
together so this I say and affirm
所以我这样说并肯定
together with the Lord that you walk no
与主一起，你走了没有
longer just as the Gentiles also walk in
更长的就像外邦人也走进来一样
the futility of their minds now look at
现在 他们的思想 无用了
what it says in the futility of their
它说的是徒劳无功的
mind what is proverbs 3:5 and 6 say
记住什么是箴言3：5和6说
don't lean on your own understanding
不依靠自己的聪明
what does it tell you in Jeremiah 17
它在耶利米书中告诉你什么17
don't trust your heart don't trust your
不信任你的心脏不信任你
feelings okay you know so you don't walk
感觉好你知道所以你不走路
in the futility of your mind as they do
你的思想是徒劳的
they're darkened in their understanding
他们的理解变暗了
they're excluded from the life of God
他们被排除在上帝的生命之外
because of the ignorance that's in them
因为他们的无知
because of the hardness of their heart
因为他们的心脏硬度
they become calloused they've given
他们变得娇媚了
themselves over to sensuality for the
他们自己的性感
practice very kind of impurity with
练习非常杂质
greediness but you did not learn Christ
贪婪， 但你没有学习基督
in this way if indeed you have heard him
这样，如果你确实听过他的话
and have been taught in him just as the
并且像他一样被教导在他身上
truth is in Jesus now Paul's in the
真理在耶稣现在保罗在
middle of his message too
他的消息中间也是
the ephesian church but he stops and he
以弗所教会，但他停下来，他
says if indeed you are in Christ so if
说如果你确实在基督里，如果
you're in the middle of a counselling
你在一个咨询的中间
series and it's a sixth week and you're
系列，它是第六周，你是
not seeing any fruit now you are not to
现在你没有见到任何水果
be a judge judge not that you be not
成为一名法官，而不是你不是
judged you cannot see the motive of
判断你看不到的动机
their heart but you are to be a fruit
他们的心，但你要成为一个水果
inspector you can see fruit what are
检查员，你可以看到水果是什么
they doing and so if you're not seeing
他们这样做，如果你没有看到
any fruit you may want to ask this same
任何水果，你可能要问这个同样的
question and Paul says you didn't learn
问题，保罗说你没有学习
Christ in this way if you're still
如果你还在，基督会这样
walking in that way you didn't learn
走路，你没有学习
that from Christ and of course in
来自基督，当然还有
Galatians 5 you have a parallel passage
加拉太书5你有平行的通道
it tells you there about the the the
它会告诉你关于它的信息
works of the flesh and now what is this
肉体的作品， 现在这是什么
passage saying to us well it's saying
通道对我们说得很好
you are no longer to walk the way you
你不再像往常一样走路
used to walk you can change all you dr.
以前你可以改变你所有的博士。
Bob I'm pretty old look in and you can't
鲍勃， 我看起来很旧，你做不到
teach old dogs new tricks you know that
教老狗你知道的新技巧
and I say to you you have an answer for
我对你说你有一个答案
that I don't really know because I'm not
我不知道，因为我不是
a dog trainer but you can change you
狗训练师，但你可以改变你
know what my mom told me when she was in
知道我妈妈在她 什么时告诉我 的
her 70s she said Robert keep growing
70多岁时，她说罗伯特继续成长
because when you get in your 70s you're
因为当你进入70多岁时，你就是这样
going to face some of the biggest
面对一些最大的
battles you've ever faced in your
你曾经遇到的战斗
spiritual walk because your mind is
因为你的思想是灵性的
going to tillis tell you you can do
去告诉你，你可以做到
stuff but your body will tell you no you
东西， 但你的身体会告诉你没有你
can't and so your mind is going and
不能， 所以你的思想正在发生
you're over at church wanting to do all
你在教堂想要做所有事情
the things that you want to do but you
你想要做的事情
can't do so you have to really learn the
不能这样做你必须真正学习
importance of prayer and that it is a
祈祷的重要性，它是一个
battle and you can fight battles there
战斗，你可以在那里打仗
but be prepared you're gonna have to
但要做好准备，你必须这样做
learn really hard battles later my mom
我的妈妈 后来学习真的很难
lived another thirty years after that
在那之后 又过了三十年
and I could tell you about some of those
我可以告诉你其中的一些
difficult battles as well but the fact
艰难的战斗， 但事实
is it says here you can change and you
它在这里说你可以改变你
are to change and God doesn't command
要改变，上帝不指挥
you to do what he won't give you the
你做他不会给你的东西
grace and the stir
恩惠和骚动
to do so then you're not to be you are
这样做，那么你就不会是你
to behave differently then in Christ
在基督里表现得与众不同
look at verses 20 and 21 you didn't
看看你没有的20和21节
learn Christ in this way if indeed you
如果你真的以这种方式学习基督
have heard him and have been taught in
听过他并且已经被教过了
him the truth is in Jesus so we've
他真相在耶稣里，所以我们已经
talked about that the truth is in Christ
谈到真理在基督里
and in proverbs 1:7 what does it tell us
在箴言1：7中它告诉我们什么
there you know the beginning of wisdom
在那里你知道智慧的开始
is the fear of the Lord is you know God
是敬畏耶和华你是否认识上帝
said it and that's good enough for me
说它，这对我来说已经足够了
and he doesn't have to say it twice if
而且他不必再说两遍了
he said it once then that's the way I
他曾经说过那就是我的方式
will live by his grace and through his
将依靠他的恩典和他的生活
strength not proudly in my own strength
力量不是以我自己的力量自豪
now as you're dealing with this the next
现在你正在处理下一个
step is you have to put off the old self
步骤是你必须推迟旧的自我
and the old man or the old self as you
和老男人还是老的自我， 你
look at verse 23 and that you 22 that in
看第23节和你22，在
reference to your former manner of life
参考你以前的生活方式
you lay aside the old self which is
你把旧的自我放在一边
being corrupted in accordance with the
因为被破坏了
lusts of the seat or the deceitful
座位的欲望或欺骗性的
desires of life on the NIV
对NIV生活的渴望
I think translates that very well the
我认为很好地翻译了
deceitful desires of life like this
像这样欺骗生活的欲望
morning I mean I'm sure that you heard
早上我的意思是我肯定你听到了
the alarm go off and you just kind of
报警熄灭 ，你只是种
popped out of bed and said wow good
从床上掉下来说哇好
morning Lord hello this is the day this
早上好，你好，这是这一天
is the day oh my what time did they say
是他们说的时间哦
where's 8:30 I'm not gonna make it by
哪里是8:30我不会成功的
8:30 I saw a few of you coming in when I
8:30我看到你们中有几个人进来
came in I didn't make it by 8:30 either
进来我也没到8点30分
okay and so you know what the deceitful
好的，所以你知道什么是欺骗性的
design I don't punch the button punch
设计我不冲冲按钮
the button punch the button I am gonna
按钮冲按钮我要去
be late for work
上班迟到了
I gotta get ripping at this point why do
我必须抓住这一点为什么
we get up because we desire no I got to
我们起床是因为我们不希望得到
get to work I want to get to that
开始工作我想要达到这个目标
seminar I'm and what am I I'm going to
研讨会我和我要去的是什么
do this because it's right what are the
这样做是因为它是正确的
deceitful desires of life you say
你说的生活的欺骗欲望
something nasty to me I'd like to say
对我来说很讨厌的东西，我想说
something nasty back you punch me
令人讨厌的东西，你打我
I don't think turn the other cheek I
我不认为转过脸颊我
think we're can i slug him and we don't
我想我们可以揍他，我们不会
they
他们
biblically when you say something old
当你说出旧的东西时，圣经
wholesome I don't think ah blessing what
卫生我不认为啊祝福是什么
could I say nice now that he's cursed me
如果他诅咒我，我能说好吗？
out we don't think that way naturally in
出我们不认为自然以这种方式
fact you have the quote in your notes
事实上，你的笔记中有引用
that someone has said when you're in
当你进去的时候有人说过
doubt about God's will consider what you
怀疑上帝会考虑你的意思
feel like doing and do the opposite and
感觉就像在做，并做相反的事情
you'll probably be pretty close to
你可能会非常接近
scripture because when we get upset we
经文，因为当我们生气时，我们
don't think biblically unless we've been
除非我们去过，否则不要以圣经的方式思考
renewing our mind praise God I had a
更新我们的心灵赞美上帝我有一个
young man come in dealing with anger
年轻人进来处理愤怒
what would be four weeks ago now he took
现在他接受了四周前的情况
this one scripture home he feeds 43130
这一个经文回家他喂43130
to he started memorizing it and
以他开始背诵它，
meditating on it and praying it back to
冥想并祈祷回来
God asking God to change when he came
上帝要求上帝在他来的时候改变
back this week he said to me he said you
本周回来他对我说他说你
know it's amazing and when I asked him
知道这很神奇，当我问他时
you know how is it going and what's
你知道它是怎么回事，是什么回事
happening so even my friends people that
发生这样即使我的朋友们说的人
have known me a long time say what
我很久都知道了什么
what's with you in fact one of them said
你怎么了，其实是他们中的一个说
what changed what are you doing that's
是什么改变了你在做什么呢
different I want to learn what you're
不同我想知道你是什么
doing coz you're not angry like you were
因为你没有像你一样生气
what's happened and he just took this
发生了什么，他就是这么做的
scripture he meditated on it he thought
经文，他想到了这一点
about I got to put away anger I got to
关于我收起怒气练到
put away wrath I got to put away malice
放下愤怒，我必须放弃恶意
I got to put away slander I got to put
我收起诽谤我得把
away those things and I got to put on a
远离这些事情，我得穿上
tender spirit and he said he'd be in
温柔的精神，他说他会在
this situation with his brothers or with
与他的兄弟或与他的这种情况
other situations and then what would
其他情况，然后会是什么
happen is this beard of God would bring
发生的是上帝的胡须会带来的
the verse to his mind and he would start
这段经文是他的想法，他会开始
thinking oh my I can't do that that's
我想我不能那样做
angry that's clamor that smell okay what
生气的吵闹，闻起来还不错
I need to be kind what could I do that
我需要善待我能做到的
would be kind and asking God to help him
会很善良，并请求上帝帮助他
and the Spirit of God was doing exactly
并且上帝的灵正在做
what the Spirit of God will do would the
上帝的圣灵会做的会
Word of God
神的话语
training him in righteousness which
以正义训练他
we'll get to in a few minutes but you
我们会在几分钟后到达你
put off the old man you deny those
推迟那个你否认那些的老头
feelings and you do what's right okay
感觉，你做正确的事
now then the next step you must be
现在，你必须做下一步
renewed in the spirit of your mind you
以你的精神更新你
renew your mind by thinking God's
通过思考上帝的更新你的心
thoughts after him you meditate on his
在他之后的想法你冥想他的
word what a psalm 119 9 to 11 say how
怎么说诗篇1199到11怎么说
can a young man keep his
一个年轻人可以保留他的
way purer by keeping it according to thy
按照你的方式保持它更纯洁
word thy word have I hid in my heart
说出你的话，我藏在心里
that I might not sin against thee
我可能不会对你犯罪
the psalmist knew this truth he knew
诗人知道他所知道的这个真理
that if a young man wanted to change his
如果一个年轻人想要改变他的
way needed to take God's Word you need
需要采取你需要的上帝话语的方法
to hide it in his heart meaning he
隐藏在他的心里意味着他
needed to think on it in his mind and in
需要在他的思想和思想中思考它
his inner being and ask God to change
他的内在存在，并求上帝改变
his way and if God's Word was there and
他的方式，如果上帝的话语在那里和
he's thinking God's thoughts after him
他在想着上帝对他的想法
then God would empower him to do what is
然后上帝会授权他去做
right and that's powerful and good
对，那是强大而好的
thinking all right so the idea then is
想着没事这样的想法则是
you must put on the new man and then
你必须穿上新男人然后
Paul gives us all these examples that we
保罗给了我们所有这些例子中，我们
just talked about a few minutes ago
刚刚谈了几分钟
change doesn't come by just I'm gonna
改变不来的只是我会
grip my teeth and I'm not gonna get
抓住我的牙齿，我不会得到
angry when I go in the house tonight
我今晚进屋时很生气
because as soon as you walk in the house
因为只要你走进房子
and the kids stuff is all over the
孩子们的东西到处都是
living room you are really upset and you
客厅你真的不高兴，你
hold it in for about a nanosecond and
把它保持大约一纳秒
then you blow up but if you go in the
然后你会爆炸，但如果你进去了
house thinking Lord what can I do that
房子在想主我能做些什么
will be kind well there's a kind
会很好，有一种
response hey Johnny notice that your
响应嘿约翰尼注意到你的
blocks are still here are you still
块仍在这里你还在吗？
praying well those oh no I could play
好好祈祷哦，不，我可以玩
with those an hour ago okay yeah can dad
与那些一小时前好吧是啊爸爸可以
help you pick them up remember the rule
帮助你记住规则
once we finish playing with it then we
一旦我们完成了它，那么我们
put it away come on I'll help you put
把它拿走来我会帮你放的
them away and then we could sit down and
他们离开然后我们可以坐下来
talk you know Johnny what what is it
跟你说约翰尼是什么意思
what are we trying to learn about
什么是我们试图了解
discipline and self-control and that
约束和自我控制 和
when we use something then we put it
当我们使用的东西然后我们把它
away when should you have put those
你什么时候放的那些
things away well you should have done it
你应该做得很好
when you finished playing with them
当你完成了他们 玩
shouldn't you and you talk with them
不应该和你谈谈他们
that's the kind response and you're
这是那种善意的反应而你
thinking in terms of that James doesn't
在 詹姆斯的思维不
take place just stopping the bad
发生就是阻止坏事
but you lay aside the old man but you
但你抛开旧的人，但你
have to put on the new man so there's a
不得不穿上新男人，所以有一个
question that I put in it what does it
我提出的问题是什么呢
mean when someone says I can't forgive
意味着有人说我不能原谅
myself people say that well first of all
我自己的人首先说的很好
you deal with the fact that they can't
你处理的事实是他们做不到
forgive themselves right and who can
原谅自己是对的，谁可以
forgive sins even the Pharisees knew
即使法利赛人知道也要原谅罪
this one right they said to themselves
他们对自己这么说吧
when Jesus said to the guy on the mat
当耶稣对垫子上的那个人说
you know your sins are forgiven they
你知道你的罪赦免了他们
thought to themselves and Jesus read
想到自己和耶稣读
their thoughts
他们的想法
nobody can forgive sin but God who's
没有人可以原谅罪，但上帝是谁
this guy think he is and so that they
这家伙认为他是，所以他们
might know that he was God then he said
他说，他可能知道他是上帝
to him pick up your mat and walk
他拿起你的垫子走路
but the idea is they knew that only God
但这个想法是他们知道只有上帝
can forgive sins you can't forgive
可以原谅你无法原谅的罪
yourself but what does somebody mean
你自己， 但有人意味着什么
when they say that I think they mean
当他们说我认为他们的意思时
look I've been an angry person all my
看我去过一个愤怒的人都是我
life I was angry yesterday 14 times I
生活我昨天生气了14次我
was angry today before 14 times I was
在我14次之前，我今天很生气
angry the day before that 24 times I was
我前24天生气了
angry the day before that I confess it I
我前一天生气，我承认了我
turn away from it and now I get angry
转身离开它，现在我生气了
again 30 seconds later and I don't see
再过30秒后，我没有看到
any change and how can God forgive me
任何改变，上帝怎么能原谅我
when I I keep coming back with the same
当II继续回来时
thing over and over and over and over
事情一遍又一遍又一遍地
and over again like one guy had an
而且像一个人一样
assignment to journal his anger he was
他的愤怒是他的愤怒
supposed to go home for the week he was
他应该回家一周
supposed to journal when did you get
应该记录你什么时候得到的
angry or what was it at the time what
生气还是那时的什么呢
was the situation what did you do in
是什么你在做 的情况
reaction what did you want
反应你想要什么
and then what should you have done at
然后呢， 你应该已经在做
the end of the first day he had 40
他有40岁的第一天结束
things on his list you know what the
在他的名单上的东西，你知道什么
last thing he wrote on his list was
他在名单上写的最后一件事是
making this list makes me angry and I'm
制作这份名单让我生气， 而且我
not doing it anymore but when he came
不这样做了，但是当他来到
back a week later for counseling to my
一个星期后回到 我的咨询
friend Bracy he still had enough
朋友Bracy他还有足够的
information from the 40 things on the
来自40件事的信息
one day list you know to work from for a
有一天， 你知道从事工作的名单
while but the idea is we say I can't
虽然这个想法是我们说我不能
forgive myself and what we mean is you
原谅自己，我们的意思是你
know how can God forgive me because I've
知道上帝怎么能原谅我，因为我已经
done this so many times before but we
之前，但我们做到了这一点太多次
have to straighten out that language
必须理顺那种语言
that is not biblical language you cannot
这不是圣经语言你不能
forgive yourself what must you do
原谅自己必须做什么
she annually repent learn what upsets
她每年都会忏悔学习什么令人不安
you and learn what is the tender-hearted
你了解什么是温柔的
and the kind response to put on in place
以及对实施的善意回应
of that and ask the Holy Spirit to give
那要求圣灵给予
you grace to change in that process so
你恩典在这一进程 中改变，因此
Paul gives the examples in this text the
保罗在本文中给出了例子
liar has to stop lying and speak the
骗子不得不停下来说话
truth in love why because we are members
爱情真相为什么，因为我们是成员
of one another
彼此的
think about it you know here's the stove
想想你知道这里的炉子
it's an electric stove so things think
事情在想，这是一个电炉
you know you can't see the flame and you
你知道你看不到火焰和你
put your hand down on there and you
把你的手放在那里和你
didn't know that your wife had had the
不知道你的妻子曾经有过
thing on and it is hot so you say to
东西，很热，所以你说
your hand
你的手
uh and it's not really that hot just
呃，它真的不那么热
stay right there you don't say that to
留在那里， 你不要说
your hand why because it's a member of
你的手为什么，因为它是一个成员
your body and it is hot and you yell and
你的身体很热，你大喊大叫
get the thing off of there so you don't
从那里得到的东西，所以你没有
lie to one another cuz you are members
彼此欺骗， 因为你是会员
of one another when I lie to you as a
相互的，当我骗你的
brother in Christ it's like what I just
在基督里的弟兄就像我一样
described what we wouldn't do with our
描述了我们不会对我们做什么
own bodies and then the thief must stop
自己的身体，然后小偷必须停止
stealing we've talked about it I got to
偷我们已经谈论它，我得到了
care enough to reach out to others the
足够小心地接触别人
speaker of unwholesome words must stop
不善言辞的说话者必须停止
those words put on words that build
那些话就是建立起来的话语
others up at the right moment and that
其他人在正确的时刻和那个
Minister Grace and the bitter angry
格蕾丝部长和苦涩的生气
wrathful clamor slanders malicious
愤怒的喧嚣诽谤恶意
people must put on kindness
人们必须表现出善意
tenderheartedness and forgiveness and so
温柔和宽恕等等
that's the pattern now if you turn to
如果你转向，这就是现在的模式
the second Timothy 3:16 you must use the
第二个提摩太3:16你必须使用
word as your tool for teaching that is
单词作为你教学的工具
reproof what you need to know and for
责备你需要知道的东西
correction and training in righteousness
矫正和正义训练
so here's an example the Word of God
所以这是上帝之道的一个例子
gives you what you need in every single
给你你在每一个需要的东西
situation and so if you were to turn to
情况如此，如果你转向
Leviticus chapter 26 you would see some
利未记第26章你会看到一些
principles there that we're going to
原则那里，我们要
talk about in just a minute but the lady
在一分钟之内 谈谈 这位女士
comes in the ladies having panic attacks
女士们有惊恐发作
the lady draught has used to have a
女士选秀曾经有过
daycare in her home and she delighted
在她家里的日托，她很高兴
and taking care of children and enjoyed
和照顾孩子，享受
it but she stopped
但她停了下来
having the daycare she used to delighted
拥有她曾经高兴的日托
having the curtains open in her home now
现在在家里打开窗帘
she keeps the curtains closed
她保持窗帘关闭
she has panic attacks where her heart
她的心脏恐慌发作
beats fast and her hands get sweaty and
快节奏，双手出汗
shaky and her mind just goes on 100
摇摇欲坠，她的思绪只有100
miles an hour and and she's just fearful
一小时一英里，她只是害怕
and fearful about almost anything and
和恐惧的几乎所有和
she's living in this fear so she comes
她生活在这种恐惧之中，所以她来了
in and so we do research for a couple of
在等我们了几个做研究
weeks we've given her assignment but we
几个星期我们已经完成了她的任务，但我们
can't find any route to what is in this
找不到任何路线
fear that she's having these this
担心她有这些
ungrounded fear this ungrounded terror
没有根据的恐惧这种无根据的恐怖
so after a few weeks I said to her this
几个星期后我跟她说了这个
morning we're gonna try an experiment
早上，我们正在做一个实验 会
now remember this is an experiment I'm
现在记住这是我的实验
trying something that we haven't tried
尝试一些我们没有尝试过的东西
before because we haven't found anything
之前因为我们没有找到任何东西
as a route to these panic attacks that
作为这些惊恐发作的途径
you're having to this ungrounded fear
你有这种无根据的恐惧
that you have so we're gonna I want you
你有， 所以我们想要你
to look with me at Leviticus 26 and in
和我在利未记26和我一起看
Leviticus 26 it tells us God says that
利未记26 它告诉我们上帝说的
if you walk with me and if you keep my
如果你和我一起走，如果你留下我的
Sabbath and you walk with me then in
安息日， 你跟我走，然后在
verse 6 of 26 then I'll grant you peace
那么我将给你带来和平
in the land and you'll lie down with no
在土地，你会躺下，没有
one making you tremble I'll eliminate
让你颤抖的一个我会消除
harmful beasts and you won't tremble so
有害的野兽，你不会颤抖
as we're walking with God in complete
因为我们完全与上帝同行
obedience he says we won't have fear
服从他说我们不会有恐惧
verse 7 will chase our enemies you know
第7节将追逐你认识的敌人
in this case five of you will chase a
在这种情况下，你们五个人会追逐一个
hundred and a hundred you will choose
你会选择一百一百
ten thousand and I'll turn toward me you
一万，我会转向我
and I'll make your land fruitful
我会让你的土地富有成效
multiply and so on but then drop down to
乘等，但随后下降到
verse 14 but if you do not obey me and
第14节， 但如果你不服从我和
you do not carry out all these
你没有执行所有这些
Commandments if instead you reject my
诫命， 如果相反你拒绝我的
statutes and if your soul of whores my
法规，如果你的妓女的灵魂，我的
ordinances so as not to carry out all my
条例， 以免执行我所有的
Commandments and so break my covenant
诫命等违背了我的约
then I in turn will do this to you I
然后我反过来会对你做这件事
will appoint over you sudden terror and
将指定你突然恐怖和
I asked her I said would you describe
我问她，我说你会形容吗？
the feeling that comes on you as sudden
突如其来的感觉
terror she said yeah that would be a
恐怖她说是的，那将是一个
good description of it okay
它很好的说明好吗
so actually what God says in this
所以上帝真的在这说了什么
passage is that sudden terror can be a
通道是突然的恐怖可以是一个
salt of sin not keeping his Commandments
罪恶的盐不遵守他的命令
so this morning I want to go with you to
所以今天早上我想和你一起去
Deuteronomy 5 and I want to read down
申命记5和我想读下来
through the Ten Commandments with you
通过十诫与你同在
and I'm just gonna say a word of
我只想说一句话
explanation and most of them really
解释，其中大多数真的
don't need any explanation I'm just
我不需要任何解释
gonna say a word of explanation and then
然后会说一句解释
you tell me if God brings anything to
你告诉我， 如果上帝带来任何东西
your mind that could be a route here of
你的思想可能是这里的一条路线
the issue that you're dealing with and
你正在处理的问题和
so I went to the Ten Commandments
所以我去了十诫
Deuteronomy chapter 5 I got down to da
申命记第5章我下到了da
shalt not commit adultery I looked up it
不要犯通奸我抬头看了
tears in her eyes and she was starting
她眼里含着泪水，她正在开始
to cry I said what's the matter she said
哭了我说她说的是什么事
well I am living with a man I said do
好吧，我和一个男人住在一起， 我说过
you understand what God thinks of that
你理解上帝对此的看法
she said yes I know it's sin are you
她说是的，我知道这是犯罪，你
willing to deal with that no I can't
愿意处理那个我不能
deal with that he's my only source of
处理他是我唯一的来源
stability right now
现在稳定
he's the only one that really comes
他是唯一真正来的人
around he's the only one that really
他是唯一真正的人
helps care for me answer what about your
帮助照顾我，回答你的问题
children while they're there but you
孩子们虽然他们在那里，但你
know they're all grown and out of the
知道他们都是成长的
home and you know they don't really show
回家，你知道他们并没有真正表现出来
that much interest and no I just can't
那么多的兴趣，不，我不能
do that I said well then do you
那样做我说得好然后你呢
understand that I can't continue to deal
明白我不能继续交易
with you she said why not I said well
和你说她为什么不说我说得好
because the book of James says that if
因为詹姆斯的书说如果
we're not obeying what we do know and I
我们不遵守我们所知道的和我
give you more things that you should be
给你更多你应该做的 事情
doing I'm just heaping more guilt on you
这样做我只会对你更加内疚
and more accountability on you we've got
我们有更多的问责制
to stop but we've got to deal with the
停下，但我们已经有了应对
one issue we know because we read in
我们知道的一个问题， 因为我们读了
Leviticus sudden terror can be sent
可以派遣利未记突然恐怖
directly by God as a result of sin and
直接由上帝作为罪和罪的结果
so then we went to proverbs 13:20 one
所以我们去了箴言13:20一个
and it says adversity pursues sinners so
它说逆境如此追求罪人
if you look at that text in Proverbs and
如果你在箴言中查看那段文字
my mind is slipping on me this morning
我的思绪今天早上在我身上滑落
so I I'm not remembering to quote it
所以我不记得引用它
exactly but in proverbs 13:20 1 this is
确切但在箴言13:201这是
what it says
它说的是什么
in the new American Standard adversity
在新的美国标准逆境中
pursues sinners but the righteous will
追求罪人， 但正义的意志
be rewarded with prosperity I said don't
得到了回报，我说没有
you want prosperity yes
你想繁荣是的
don't you want God to bless you yes well
你不求上帝保佑是你很好
then you gotta forsake this sin because
然后你必须放弃这个罪，因为
you can't continue to cover it and make
你不能继续掩盖它，使
allowance for it and expect that God
允许它并期待上帝
will bless you because if you look at
会祝福你， 因为如果你看看
proverbs 28 and verse 14 it says how
谚语28和14节说明如何
blessed is the man who fears always but
总是有福的男人总是害怕
he who hardens his heart will fall into
会使他的心变硬的人会陷入其中
calamity and in verse 13 it says he who
灾难和第13节它说他是谁
conceals his transgression will not
隐瞒他的违法行为不会
prosper but he who confesses and
繁荣， 但他承认和
forsakes them will find compassion I
放弃他们会找到同情我
can't give it up
不能放弃
okay then you know it's life's gonna get
好的，那么你知道它的生命会得到
worse not gonna get better if you're
更糟糕的是如果你没有变得更好
God's child he as your heavenly Father
上帝的孩子， 他是你的天父
will continue to discipline you because
将继续纪律你，因为
we do know for certain right now this is
我们现在肯定知道这是
an issue you need to deal with I can't
一个问题，你需要处理我不能
do it so she went stop coming to church
这样做她就不再去教堂了
year later she came back I got to deal
一年后，她回来了我的交易
with this she confessed her sin
她承认了她的罪
she forsake the relationship didn't have
她抛弃了没有的关系
any more panic attacks I'm reading from
我正在读的更多恐慌症
a letter that she sent me ten years
一封信，她给我发了10年
seven years later dear Bob and Mary
七年后亲爱的鲍勃和玛丽
she's writing to us from a vacation
她正在度假给我们写信
haven't had a tranquilizer since I
从那以后我没有镇静剂
counseled with you seven years ago not
七年前劝告你的 不是
even when I took a bumpy flight in the
即使我在飞机上崎岖不平
Dominican Republic to Puerto Rico on a
多米尼加共和国到波多黎各
four passenger toy-sized plane with one
四个乘客玩具大小的飞机与一个
wing flapping underneath that plane
机翼在那架飞机下面拍打着
where the everlasting arms and it is so
永恒的武器就在那里
exhilarating to see his beautiful
令人振奋，看到他的美丽
islands of emerald green in the blue
翡翠绿色的岛屿在蓝色
green waters of the warm Caribbean my
温暖的加勒比海的绿色水域我的
thoughts and prayers are with you and
思想和祈祷与你同在
all the wonderful work that God is doing
上帝正在做的所有奇妙的工作
wait a minute she's got the shades
等一下，她有阴影
pulled you know most of us get nervous
拉你知道我们大多数人都很紧张
about flying in those little toy sized
关于那些小玩具的飞行
planes you know there's a total change
飞机你知道这是一个彻底的改变
in this lady's life how did I know
在这位女士的生活中，我怎么知道
because the Word of God is sufficient
因为神的话就足够了
for teaching do you have a plan
对于教学，你有一个计划
for reading the Word of God you you
为了阅读上帝的话语，你
could read two chapters in the Old
可以阅读Old中的两章
Testament and one in Psalms and one in
约和一个诗篇，一个在
Proverbs and two in the new every day
谚语和每天两个新的谚语
and what you would do is in one year
你会做的是一年
you'll read through the Old Testament
你会读完旧约
once you'll read through proverbs twelve
一旦你通过谚语十二读
times you'll read through Psalms twice
你会读过Psalms两次
and you read through the New Testament
你读完了新约
twice if you just follow that six
如果你只是遵循这六个，那么两次
chapters a day and just read I'm not
一天的章节，只是阅读我不是
talking about study and I'm talking
谈论学习，我在说话
about reading you know just you read
关于阅读你知道只是你读
through the text
通过文本
well maybe note one verse that stood out
好吧也许请注意一首突出的诗句
to you or maybe highlight one verse but
对你或者可能突出一节经文但是
just read and then when you're in this
只是阅读，然后当你在这里
situation God will take what you read
情况上帝会把你所读的内容
this morning bring it to your mind and
今天早上把它带到你的脑海里
it'll apply in that situation I've been
它适用于那种情况我一直都是
reading in Leviticus I've seen sudden
在利未记中读书我突然看到了
terror as a result of sin and God works
由于罪和上帝的工作而产生的恐怖
and it's the Word of God that provides
这是上帝的话语所提供的
teaching it revives reproof you know you
教它重新责备你知道你
put give them the Word of God this is
放给他们神的话，这是
what God's Word says thou shalt not
上帝的话语说不出你的意思
commit adultery I don't believe the Word
犯奸淫我不相信这个词
of God okay
上帝好吗
I'm standing in front of you with a 357
我站在你的面前有一个357
Magnum and I tell you give me your
马格南和我告诉你给我你的
wallet I don't believe that's a real gun
钱包我不相信那是真正的枪
I don't believe it's loaded I'll pull
我不相信它会加载我会拉
the trigger and I'll make you a believer
触发器，我会让你成为一个信徒
as well as make a hole right through you
以及在你身上打个洞
big going in and big going out all right
大进去，大出去好吧
I don't care if you don't believe that
如果你不相信，我不在乎
it's a 357 and it's loaded if I know it
这是一个357，如果我知道它就会被加载
is you carry the 357 it is the sword of
是您随身携带的357是剑
God it's sharp it's two-engine pierces
上帝，这是两个引擎刺穿 的尖锐
right to the very thoughts and the minds
正确的思想和思想
of people I can't tell you how many
人我不能告诉你多少
times I was talking with people after
我以后和别人说话
the service on a Sunday morning and they
星期天早上的服务和他们
would say to me Pastor Bob were you in
会告诉我鲍勃牧师你是谁
our house this morning
今天早上我们的房子
answer no Pastor Bob how did you know
回答没有牧师鲍勃你怎么知道的
what I've been dealing with this week I
本周我一直在处理的事情
don't God knows God takes his word and
不要上帝知道上帝接受他的话语
he applies it to the heart and that's
他将它应用于心脏，那就是
the power of the word of God it corrects
它纠正了上帝之道的力量
and it trains in righteousness the young
它以正义的方式训练年轻人
man that had the anger issued takes the
发出愤怒的男人接受了
verse memorizes the worst hides it in
诗歌记忆最糟糕的隐藏它
his heart ask God to change his heart
他的心要求上帝改变他的心
he's in the middle of the situation he's
他正处于这种情况的中间
arguing with his brother or his roommate
和他的兄弟或他的室友争吵
God brings it to mine God stops him he
上帝把它带到了我的上帝阻止了他
thinks kindness he thinks
他认为善意
tenderheartedness he changes his action
温柔的他改变了他的行动
and God works
上帝的作品
now the thing is you asked for change
现在问题是你要求改变
according to God's Word John 15:7 if you
根据上帝的话约翰福音15：7如果你
abide in me and my words abide in you
住在我里面，我的话语住在你里面
you can ask what you will and I will do
你可以问你会做什么，我会做什么
it in John 15:7 that same thing as you
它在约翰福音15：7同样的事情，你
abide in his words you abide in Christ
你要遵守他 在基督里的话
you abide in his words to abide in
你用他的话说遵守遵守 中
Christ is to trust him for salvation to
基督要相信他得救
abide in Christ is to trust him for what
住在基督里就是信靠他
you need right now this minute this day
这一天你现在需要这一分钟
you see you cannot live a moment without
你看，没有你就活不了
Christ what can you do without Christ
没有基督你能做什么呢？
Zippo nada nothing what can you do in
Zippo nada没什么可以做的
Christ I can do all things through
基督我可以做所有事情
Christ who strengthens me
基督谁加强了我
and that's the power of the word of God
这就是上帝之道的力量
working in your life you have to ask God
在你的生活中工作，你必须问上帝
for change you ask whatever you will and
为了改变你会问你想要什么
it will be done for you
它将为你完成
so you ask him to change your heart and
所以你要求他改变你的心
your life this is the renewing of the
你的生活，这是更新的
mind as you ask for that and then think
当你问这个然后思考时，请记住
about it you ask for change according to
关于它，你要求根据改变
the word what does John first John 5 14
这个词是约翰第一约翰5 14
and 15 remember John's in the upper room
15记得约翰在上层房间
he hers the Upper Room discourse he
他是上议院的话语
hears Jesus teach about you are the you
听到耶稣教导你是你
are the branches and I am the vine you
是树枝，我是你的葡萄树
got to abide in me abide in me of my
一定要在我里面，在我遵守我的
words abide in you ask what you will now
你会问你现在会说些什么
how does he interpret that when he
他怎么解释那个
writes his epistle in first John chapter
在约翰的第一章写下他的书信
5 he says this and this is the
5 他说这就是这个
confidence you have before me if you ask
如果你问，你有信心摆在我面前
anything according to his will you know
根据他的意愿， 你知道什么
that he hears the requests and you know
他听到了请求，你知道
that you have the requests you have made
你有你提出的要求
of him how do you know he will hear your
他怎么知道他会听你的
prayer pray according to his word so why
祈祷按照他的话祈祷，为什么呢
then does the outline that you have of
然后做你的大纲
the discovering wonderful thing why does
该发现美妙的事情为什么
it say observation interpretation
它说观察解释
application prayer pray it back to God
应用祈祷祈祷它回到上帝
you take the verse let no unwholesome
你接受这节经文就不要让不健康
word proceed from your mouth but only
单词从你的嘴里开始， 但只是
such a word as is good for edification
这样的话因为是很好的启迪
according to the need of the moment but
根据当下的需要 但是
it might give grace to those who hear
它可能会给那些听到的人带来恩惠
and you turn it into a prayer look at
然后你把它变成祈祷的样子
the prayer in the fourth column on that
第四栏中的祷告
sample sheet father show me the things
样本表父亲给我看的东西
that I say that are hurtful and cutting
我说这是伤害和切割
and help me to stop saying words that
并帮我停止说出那些话
are unwholesome help me to say words
是不善的帮我说话
that will build people up today
这将在今天建立人民
change them so you take the verse and
改变它们， 以便你接受这节经文
put it on this side of the card you take
把它放在卡片的这一侧
the prayer and you put it on this side
祈祷，你把它放在这一边
of the card and then you keep the verse
卡片然后你保留这节经文
in your pocket so if you're working in
在你的口袋里， 所以如果你在工作
my case on the idea that I'm always
关于我总是这样的想法
saying dumb things right at once without
说愚蠢的事情就在一次无
thinking and I'm always getting mad at
思考，我总是生气
an drop of a hat I'm memorizing proverbs
一滴帽子， 我正在记住谚语
1216 a fools anger is known at once but
1216 傻瓜的怒气一下子就知道了
a prudent man conceals dishonor and then
一个谨慎的人隐瞒羞辱然后
in the ESV it says the vexation of a
在ESV中，它说的是一种烦恼
fool is known at once but the prudent
傻瓜立刻就知道但是谨慎
ignores an insult I'm trying to learn to
忽略侮辱我努力去学习
ignore insults just ignore it you don't
忽略侮辱不理它，你不
have to respond to that stuff a fools
必须回应那些傻瓜
anger is known in a moment so you turn
一时之间就会知道愤怒，所以你转过身来
it over and there's a prayer father
它结束了，有一个祷告的父亲
grant me your grace as only you can to
赐予我你的恩典，因为只有你可以
control my anger and give me the joy of
控制我的愤怒，给我带来快乐
learning to ignore an insult help me to
学会忽视侮辱帮助我
cover over a dishonor that is done to me
掩盖了对我做的羞辱
you know what you're in the middle of it
你知道你在它的中间
you respond and God immediately brings
你回应，上帝立即带来
the scripture to your mind and enables
经文给你的想法和启用
you to begin to respond differently in
你开始以不同的方式回应
that situation and then the fact of the
这种情况，然后这个事实
matter is you got to practice your plan
问题是你必须练习你的计划
Hebrews 5:14 talks about the fact that
希伯来书5:14谈到了这个事实
we who are growing in the Lord we
我们在主里成长的 我们
practice the plan it doesn't just happen
实践计划它不仅仅发生
automatically it says they're solid food
自动它说它们是固体食物
is for the mature who because of
是因为成熟的人
practice you know my roommate in college
练习你在大学里认识我的室友
I'll never forget let me sing for you
我永远不会忘记让我为你歌唱
again this is what he would sing to me
这也是他会对我唱歌的原因
when I was being inconsistent brother
当我和哥哥不一致的时候
Bob you need to practice practice what
鲍勃， 你需要练习练习什么
you preach
你讲道
he's from the south okay he had a little
他来自南方，他有一点点
intonation there but I would hit that up
语调有，但我会打的起来
if I'm doing anything inconsistent I
如果我做任何不一致的事情我
would hear it practice practice well
会听到它练习练习
it's preach all right and you got to do
它宣扬没事，你该怎么做
it
它
you got to practice what is first
你必须先练习第一个
Timothy chapter 4 and verses 7 and 8 say
提摩太第4章和第7节和第8节说
and sometimes it's convenient using this
有时使用它很方便
computer Bible you can get there quick
电脑圣经你可以快速到达那里
I'll bet I can beat you on most sword
我敢打赌，我可以用大多数剑击败你
journals for this thing but have nothing
这个东西的期刊却什么都没有
to do with worldly fables fit only for
做与世俗寓言只适合
old women on the other hand discipline
另一方面，老年妇女纪律严明
yours
你的
for the purpose of godliness for bodily
为了身体的敬虔目的
discipline is only a little profit
纪律只是一点利润
it is a profit you need to exercise
这是你需要运用的利润
because you've been given this body and
因为你已经得到了这个身体
it's the temple the Holy Spirit you
这是 圣灵你的圣殿
ought to take care of it but some little
应该采取的，但一些小的护理
profit godliness is profitable for all
利益敬虔对所有人都有利可图
things since it holds promise for the
事情因为它有希望
present life and also for the life to
现在的生活，也为生命而存在
come and the word in here about
来这里的话就是关于
discipline is gimnasio from which we get
纪律是我们得到的 gimnasio
our word gymnasium you need to be in
我们需要你的体育馆一词
God's gym
上帝的健身房
the Puritans used to call it Spiritual
清教徒过去常称之为精神
Exercises we call it devotions which
演习我们叫它奉献这
sounds more disciplined more like you're
听起来更有纪律，更像你
you're in the gym I think the Spiritual
你在健身房我认为精神
Exercises does so think about it in
练习就是这么想的
terms of that verse that we just looked
我们刚看过的那节经文的用语
at and you are to put off on wholesome
在，你要推迟健康
words put on words that edify put on
把文字放在上面的文字上
good words that edify at the right time
在正确的时间启发的好词
and that Minister grace so you take the
那部长恩，所以你拿走了
scripture you memorize the scripture if
经文你记住经文如果
he's in 429 let no unwholesome word
他在429不要说任何不健康的话
proceed out of you out of your mouth but
从你的嘴里出来，但是
only such a word is this good for
只有这样一个词才有用
edification according to need of the
根据需要进行教育
moment that it might minister grace to
它可以为恩典服务的那一刻
those who hear and you begin to define
那些听到并开始定义的人
word all that identification that's a
所有这些标识都是一个字
big word for building other people up
建立其他人的大词
for saying something encouraging
说些鼓励的话
encouraging well what is unwholesome is
鼓励那些不健康的事情
that just you know the f-word and
只是你知道F-字和
blasphemy no it's it's actually means
亵渎不，这实际上意味着
anything that corrupts anything that
任何破坏任何东西的东西
pulls somebody down anything that makes
有人拉下来任何使
them feel uncomfortable and then you're
他们感到不舒服，然后你就是
gonna say words at the right time that
会在合适的时间说出话来
will build them up and that will
将建立他们，那将
minister grace so when your husband
部长恩，所以当你的丈夫
walks in the door and says what about
走进门， 说什么
world you've been doing all day a woman
你一整天都在做一个女人的世界
a place is a mess
一个地方是一团糟
instead of saying in well wasn't really
而不是说好，不是真的
you've been to an old man you know you
你去过一个认识你的老头
you say something like sweetheart it's
你说像甜心这样的东西
so good to have you home I appreciate so
很高兴你回家我非常感激
much all the work that you do and
你做的所有工作和
providing for our family and you respond
为我们的家庭提供服务并做出回应
with a blessing instead because you're
祝福，而不是因为你
gonna minister grace with your words
要用你的话语来服侍恩典
and you do that by this kind of a
你是通过这种方式做到的
process where you put off the old man
你推迟老人的过程
you put on the new man through the
你穿上了新男人
renewing of your mind and asking God to
更新你的思想，并求上帝
give you that Grace and the power to
给你那格蕾丝和力量
change as you walk with him and on that
当你和他一起走路时改变
sample for example there are some things
例如样品有一些东西
that you put down as you're working on
当你正在努力时 ，你放下了
application and that is I got to stop
申请，那是我必须停止
saying things like can't you ever do
说你不能做的事情
anything right or you're always ten
什么都对，或者你总是十岁
minutes later can't you ever listen the
几分钟后你不能听
first time and I'm gonna make a list of
第一次和我要让名单
the five people closest to me and the
最接近我和我的五个人
ten character qualities I appreciate
我很欣赏十个品质
about them and I'm gonna purpose to
关于他们，我会目的
compliment one person each day and if
每天赞美一个人，如果
you look down there dick Jane and Johnny
你看那里家伙珍妮和约翰尼
Harry and Susie and you see underneath
哈利和苏西，你看到下面
them and there there's ten different
他们在那里有十种不同
character qualities under each one of
每一个人的品质
those names so you could go down through
那些名字， 所以你可以通过
that list you could start practicing
那个名单你可以开始练习了
that this week in your home you know
本周在你家里你知道
take your wife take your husband take
带你的妻子带你的丈夫带走
your children go down through this list
你的孩子通过这个列表
and make a list of the things that are
并且使 这是 事情的清单
good about them and then purpose that
对他们有好感，然后就是目的
every day you are gonna build them up
每天你都会建立它们
for one of those things you're gonna be
对于其中一件你会成为的东西
looking for when they show courteousness
寻找他们表现出礼貌的时候
or when they show kindness or when they
或者当他们表现出善意或何时表现出善意
show good discipline or when they show
表现出良好的纪律或表现出来
cautiousness or when they show
谨慎或何时表现出来
gratefulness and you're gonna say you
感激，你会说你
know I really appreciated the way you
知道我真的很感激你的方式
were grateful to that clerk and the
感谢那个职员和
store today John that's really good
今天约翰，这真的很好
makes dad's hard to sing when you do
当你这么做时 ，爸爸很难唱歌
things like that and you know you build
这样的事情，你知道你打造
them up and you practice the Word of God
他们起来，你练习上帝的话语
and it changes our life okay we've done
它改变了我们的生活，好吧我们已经完成了
a brief summary of the process of
过程的简要概述
biblical change and now you need to
圣经的改变，现在你需要
practice what you've learned
练习你学到的东西